Guide to the Coca Crystal Video Recordings and Papers MSS.468
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II. The Coca Crystal Show: If I Can't Dance, You Can Keep Your Revolution, 1977-1995
  - Segment featuring Cesar Chavez to mark his death, Tuli Kupferberg, May 4, 1993; cuid29869 (Box 20, U-matic 468_270)
    A note on the tape says "Audio problem - hum throughout"
  - Aron Kay, May 11, 1993; cuid29945 (Box 25, U-matic 468_348)
  - Panel on Public Access, June 8, 1993; cuid29946 (Box 25, U-matic 468_349)
  - Iris Lord, Lannes Kenfield, Tuli Kupferberg, June 29, 1993; cuid29947 (Box 25, U-matic 468_350)
  - Lannes Kenfield, Tuli Kupferberg, Michael Caesar "The Pope of Dope", July 6, 1993; cuid29851 (Box 18, Vhs 468_252)
    Notes on the tape regarding the date are conflicting - "7/6," "7/27," and "Repeat 7/20"
  - John Penley, Jim Slim, Saugerties Air Drop, August 9, 1993; cuid29830 (Box 17, U-matic 468_228)
  - Cesar Chavez, August 10, 1993; cuid29846 (Box 18, U-matic 468_247)
  - Tuli Kupferberg, Jasmine, Kevin O'Neill, September 4, 1993; cuid29600 (Box 18, U-matic 468_239)
    Duration: 32 minutes
  - Joe Christ, David Peel, Lannes Kenfield, Tuli Kupferberg, September 21, 1993; cuid29948 (Box 25, U-matic 468_351)
  - David Peel, Lannes Kenfield, Tuli Kupferberg, September 28, 1993; cuid29949 (Box 26, U-matic 468_352)
  - Bruce Kayton, Radical Walking Tour, October 12, 1993; cuid29950 (Box 25, U-matic 468_353)
  - Paul Krassner, October 19, 1993; cuid29841 (Box 18, U-matic 468_242)
  - The Pope, October 26, 1993; cuid29951 (Box 26, U-matic 468_354)
  - Dr. Aaron A. Moss, Bruce Kayton, November 2, 1993; cuid29952 (Box 26, U-matic 468_355)
  - Judith Malina, November 23, 1993; cuid29853 (Box 19, U-matic 468_254)
    Film date November 23, 1993; air date January 11, 1994.
  - Abbie Hoffman's Birthday, November 30, 1993; cuid29953 (Box 26, U-matic 468_356)
  - Aaron A. Moss, Joe Christ, December 14, 1993; cuid29954 (Box 26, U-matic 468_357)
  - Bruce Kayton, December 21, 1993; cuid29852 (Box 19, U-matic 468_253)
  - Lori Rizzo, January 25, 1994; cuid29955 (Box 26, U-matic 468_358)
  - Jill Hoffman, February 1, 1994; cuid29956 (Box 26, U-matic 468_359)
  - Vladimir Urban, Mamala, February 15, 1994; cuid29957 (Box 26, U-matic 468_360)
  - Film about Jasmine, February 22, 1994; cuid29854 (Box 19, U-matic 468_255)
  - Kevin O'Neill, Video of Junot's 7th Birthday!, March 1, 1994; cuid29958 (Box 26, U-matic 468_361)
  - Michael Sullivan, March 8, 1994; cuid29959 (Box 26, U-matic 468_362)
  - Steve Ben Israel, March 15, 1994; cuid29888 (Box 21, U-matic 468_289)
  - The Pope, Bruce Kayton, Radical Walking Tours, March 22, 1994; cuid29889 (Box 21, U-matic 468_290, Box 29, Vhs 468_406)
  - Danny Schecter, Global Vision, March 29, 1994; cuid29890 (Box 21, U-matic 468_291)
  - Danny Schecter, April 5, 1994; cuid29891 (Box 21, U-matic 468_292)
  - Jim Mason, April 12, 1994; cuid29892 (Box 21, U-matic 468_293)
  - Jim Mason, April 19, 1994; cuid29893 (Box 21, U-matic 468_294)
  - Aldous Huxley Tapes, Lannes Kenfield, Answering Phones, April 26, 1994; cuid29894 (Box 22, U-matic 468_295)
    Dduration: 30 minutes
  - Ira Cohen, May 3, 1994; cuid29895 (Box 22, U-matic 468_296)
    This episode also features Brian Benson, Lannes Kenfield, and Bruce Kayton.
  - Peter Lanborn Wilson, Bruce Kayton, May 17, 1994; cuid29896 (Box 22, U-matic 468_297)
  - Segment featuring the Coca Crystal Show Promo Tape, June 14, 1994; cuid29897 (Box 22, U-matic 468_298)
  - Meet the Staff!, June 21, 1994; cuid29898 (Box 22, U-matic 468_299)
  - Joe Christ, June 28, 1994; cuid29899 (Box 22, U-matic 468_300)
    This episode also features Tuli Kupferberg, Bruce Kayton, and Lannes Gardens.
  - Nancy A. Collins, July 5, 1994; cuid29900 (Box 22, U-matic 468_301)
    This episode also features Lannes Kenfield, Tuli Kupferberg, and Bruce Kayton.
  - Mary Lou - Squatter, Andrew Hoffman, July 12, 1994; cuid29960 (Box 26, U-matic 468_363)
  - Magda Echerarria, Andrew Hoffman, July 19, 1994; cuid29926 (Box 24, U-matic 468_329, Box 29, Vhs 468_407)
    468_329 duration: 30 minutes
  - Kevin O'Neill, July 26, 1994; cuid29961 (Box 26, U-matic 468_364)
  - Les Levine, August 2, 1994; cuid29962 (Box 26, U-matic 468_365)
  - Andrew Hoffman, Tuli Kupferberg, August 17, 1994; cuid29963 (Box 27, U-matic 468_366)
  - Aaron Kay, August 23, 1994; cuid29964 (Box 27, U-matic 468_367)
  - Alex - Community Garden, August 30, 1994; cuid29965 (Box 27, U-matic 468_368)
  - Judith Malina, Steve Ben Israel, September 13, 1994; cuid29966 (Box 27, U-matic 468_369)
  - Judith Malina, Steve Ben Israel, Mike Chance, September 20, 1994; cuid29967 (Box 27, U-matic 468_370)
  - Christine Kelly, Tuli Kupferberg, October 7, 1994; cuid29968 (Box 27, U-matic 468_371)
  - David Levine, October 14, 1994; cuid29927 (Box 24, U-matic 468_330)
    This episode also features regulars Tuli Kupferberg and Bruce Kayton. A note on the tape says "Archive: Jango Edwards"
  - Flo Fox, Photographer and Activist, October 21, 1994; cuid29969 (Box 27, U-matic 468_372)
    This episode also features commentary by Tuli Kupferberg, archive tape with Jasmine, and answering phones with Coca Crystal.
  - Steve "Wildman" Brill, October 28, 1994; cuid29970 (Box 27, U-matic 468_373)
    This episode also features commentary with Tuli Kupferberg, archive tape "The Pope is a Pedophile" with Kevin O'Neill, and Radical Walking Tours with Bruce Kayton.
  - Bill Schaap, Tuli Kupferberg, November 4, 1994; cuid29971 (Box 27, U-matic 468_374)
    Duration: 30 Minutes
  - Tape Archives, November 11, 1994; cuid29972 (Box 27, U-matic 468_375)
  - Johanna Lawrenson, America Hoffman, November 18, 1994; cuid29973 (Box 27, U-matic 468_376)
    This episode also features commentary by Tuli Kupferberg and answering phones with Coca and company.
  - Johanna Lawrenson, America Hoffman, November 25, 1994; cuid29974 (Box 27, U-matic 468_377)
    This episode also features commentary by Tuli Kupferberg and Radical Walking Tours with Bruce Kayton.
  - Paul Krassner, December 9, 1994; cuid29975 (Box 27, U-matic 468_378)
  - John Valadez - "Passin' It On", December 16, 1994; cuid29976 (Box 27, U-matic 468_379)
  - Kevin O'Neill; Archive Tape - Jim Neu, Roger Babb "Eye Witness", December 23, 1994; cuid29928 (Box 24, U-matic 468_331)
  - James Learned from Act Up!, Global Peace Walk, January 13, 1995; cuid29977 (Box 28, U-matic 468_380)
    This episode also features commentary with Tuli Kupferberg and answering phones with Coca and guests.
  - Judith Malina, Joanie Fritz, The Living Theatre, January 20, 1995; cuid29978 (Box 28, U-matic 468_381)
    This episode also features commentary by Tuli Kupferberg and a clip with Dan Einbender: "This is just an advertisement for peace"
  - Gary Goodrow, February 10, 1995; cuid29979 (Box 28, U-matic 468_382)
  - John Tytel, The Living Theatre, February 17, 1995; cuid29980 (Box 28, U-matic 468_383)
    This episode also features commentary by Tuli Kupferberg, a Vincent Titus poem, and answering phones with Coca Crystal.
  - Steve Ben Israel, February 24, 1995; cuid29981 (Box 28, U-matic 468_384)
    This episode also features commentary by Tuli Kupferberg and a surprise Archive Tape.
  - Death Penalty - The Living Theatre, Bruce Kayton, Tuli Kupferberg, March 10, 1995; cuid29982 (Box 28, U-matic 468_385)
  - Tom Hachtman, March 17, 1995; cuid29929 (Box 24, U-matic 468_332)
    This episode also features Tuli Kupferberg and music by Grotz de Pooty.
  - Flo Fox, March 31, 1995; cuid29983 (Box 28, U-matic 468_386)
  - Ray Gaspard, April 7, 1995; cuid29984 (Box 28, U-matic 468_387)
  - Imani Henry, April 21, 1995; cuid29985 (Box 28, U-matic 468_388)
    This episode also features Tuli Kupferberg and answering phones.
  - Stephen Coleman, April 28, 1995; cuid29986 (Box 28, U-matic 468_389)
    This episode also features Tuli Kupferberg and Bruce Kayton.
  - Sue Harris, May 12, 1995; cuid29987 (Box 28, U-matic 468_390)
  - Jelayne Miles, May 19, 1995; cuid29988 (Box 28, U-matic 468_391)
  - Ash Wednesday - Paul Krassner, Earl Manning, Nancy Michelson, Marty Brown, Undated; cuid29842 (Box 18, U-matic 468_243)
  - Coca Show 2, Undated; cuid30012 (Box 30, Vhs 468_423)
    Duration: 31 minutes.
  - Commander Video New Years Eve Show, December 31; cuid30009 (Box 30, U-matic 468_419)
  - Dean Kuipers, David Peel, Undated; cuid29616 (Box 36, U-matic 468_240)
  - Ed Meadows, December 17; cuid30008 (Box 30, U-matic 468_418)
  - Flo Fox, Undated; cuid30037F (Box 32, U-matic 468_458)
  - Memorial for Vincent Titus, Undated; cuid29870 (Box 20, U-matic 468_271)
- Series III. Biographical and Promotional Materials, 1977-2012
  Series III. Biographical and Promotional Materials includes telivision appearances and interviews by Coca Crystal, as well as recordings of events that she went to, on U-matic and VHS video tapes. It also includes a Certificate of Appreciation awarded to Cyrstal by the Metropolitan Playhouse in 2012.
  - Bavaria: Meet the Filmmaker, Spiro Carras, Undated; cuid30021 (Box 31, U-matic 468_436)
    Duration: 30 minutes; Preservation Note: Tape required incubation, first 4 minutes of content had no video.
  - Berlei Morning Show CH-7, December 9, 1983; cuid30023 (Box 31, U-matic 468_438)
  - Best of Coca #2: Jim Mason, 1977-1995; cuid30013 (Box 30, U-matic 468_424)
  - Best of Coca #3: Coca Crystal, Vincent Titus, Leopold Maler, Leslie Kendall, Steve Ben Israel, 1977-1995; cuid30014 (Box 30, U-matic 468_425)
    Starring Coca Crystal and Vincent Titus (Singing), Leopold Maler, Subway Gender Test with Leslie Kendall, Phones, Nonsense-A-Milla Street (Pot Report) Comedy with Steve Ben Israel, Returning the Shah
  - Best of Coca #4: Pop Top, 1977-1995; cuid30015 (Box 30, U-matic 468_426)
  - Caldwell Taylor, Undated; cuid30024 (Box 31, U-matic 468_439)
    Duration: 60 minutes; Preservation note: Tape required incubation
  - Certificate of Appreciation Presented to Jackie Diamond from the Metropolitan Playhouse, 2012; cuid29617 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Coca Crystal's Message From Home, Undated; cuid30037O (Box 32, Vhs 468_464)
    This footage includes outdoor shots and the cameraman playing the guitar. It was featured in the episode that aired May 11, 1988.
  - Coca on NBC, June 11, 1992; cuid30028 (Box 31, U-matic 468_443)
    Duration: 30 minutes; Preservation note: Tape required incubation
  - Ganesh Baba, Undated; cuid30022 (Box 31, U-matic 468_437)
  - Gus's Birthday / Shalom America MCTV, May 28, 1991; cuid30018 (Box 31, U-matic 468_429)
    This may be a recycled tape - "Shalom America MCTV" may be a previous title, and the date 5/28/1991 may be innacurate for the current recording on the tape.
  - G.W. Hospital Stakeout, April 4, 1981; cuid30017 (Box 30, U-matic 468_428)
    Note on tape says "Recyclable Tape for Coca Crystal's Show"
  - "No Holds Barred," CBS Documentary on Coca Crystal and Friends, Undated; cuid30020 (Box 31, Vhs 468_433, U-matic 468_434, 468_435)
  - Promo Tapes, Undated; cuid30019 (Box 31, U-matic 468_430, 468_431, 468_432, Box 32, U-matic 468_453)
  - Refuge Temple Night Service Tape #3 / Mary Woronov "Eating Raoul", Undated; cuid30026 (Box 31, U-matic 468_441)
  - Stephen Holt Interviewing Pat McCorkle and Richard Wherrett, August, 1988; cuid30027 (Box 31, Vhs 468_442)
- Series IV. Polar Bear News, 1983-1984
  Series IV. Polar Bear News includes video recordings of the news segment, which was created by a friend of Crystal's, on U-matic and VHS tapes.
  - Polar Bear News (Shot at Home - First Half), August 31, 1983; cuid30032 (Box 32, Vhs 468_447)
  - Polar Bear News, September 22, 1983; cuid30029 (Box 32, U-matic 468_444)
  - Polar Bear News, September 29, 1983; cuid30030 (Box 32, U-matic 468_445)
  - Polar Bear News, December 30, 1983; cuid30031 (Box 32, U-matic 468_446)
  - Polar Bear News, May 24, 1984; cuid30035 (Box 32, Vhs 468_448, 468_450)
  - Polar Bear News, August 1, 1984; cuid30034 (Box 32, Vhs 468_449)
  - Polar Bear News, Undated; cuid30036 (Box 32, Vhs 468_451, 468_452)